lilithfair.com 2014-06-30

# Sarah McLachlan - SarahMcLachlan.com Privacy Policy | Sarah McLachlan

Sarah McLachlan, Sarah McLachlan Entertainment Corporation and this site care about your privacy. This privacy policy is available to share with you what we collect in SarahMcLachlan.com and how we intend to use it. By visiting this site your visit is subject to this privacy policy, and you agree to the terms of it.

## What Information We Will Collect

There are many places at our sites where you can share your personal information with us, and where you can communicate with others.

## Registration

If you register on SarahMclachlan.com we might request such information as your contact information (examples:  name, email address, mailing address, etc.), demographic information (examples: your city, country, age, gender, etc.), and profile data (examples:  music preferences, entertainment practices, favorite songs  etc). You may be assigned a site username and/or password. For our internal purposes, we use this information to communicate with you and provide the services you have requested, and to provide a more personalized experience on our sites. For example, your registration may allow you to use and post to site message boards, create site profiles, etc. We use aggregate demographic and profile information in order to improve our service, for research purposes, marketing/promotional purposes and/or for industry reporting purposes, among others. By visiting our site, you affirmatively consent to our collection and use of your data.

## Newsletters and Other Communications 

Our registered users may receive newsletters, email communications, or communications through other channels for, among other purposes, the promotion and marketing of a product or service from SarahMclachlan.com and business partners, and we may also offer other visitors to our sites the opportunity to sign up to receive such information. When there is a separate sign-up for newsletters, we ask for contact information such as name and email address, and, sometimes, demographic and profile information. By visiting our site, you affirmatively consent to our collection and use of your data. We use this information in the same manner as we use the contact information in the registration process described above. Recipients of our mailings can unsubscribe by following instructions that may appear at the end of email communications.

## Communications with Sarah McLachlan and Team

We love hearing from you and suggest using our contact form or the various social business platforms. We may retain your emails and other information you submit to us for our internal purposes, to help us to serve you better and to increase direct communication for a better overall experience for you.

## Communications with Friends

We may offer features where you can send information to others, such as e-cards or "Share With A Friend" features. We will use the contact information you enter for your friends to send the email or e-card.

## Interactive and Community Features

We will be adding interactive and community features such as message boards, chat, email accounts, short message service (SMS), instant messaging, etc. All information posted or sent through these features may be publicly available, and you should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personal information (e.g., user name, email address, phone number) through these features, that information can be collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited communications from other people. By accessing these features and disclosing personal information, you affirmatively consent to the distribution of your personal information as described above. Users’ posts may be publicly and/or internally associated with their profiles/screen-names. Users are solely responsible for the content of messages they post or send on public forums. Please note this is only the information that you the user chooses to enter.

## Contests, Sweepstakes and Surveys

We may also have contests, sweepstakes and surveys at our sites. When you enter or participate in them, we request contact information from you (such as your full name, email address, mailing address, and telephone number) and may also request demographic or profile information. We will use the information you provide for the purpose of conducting the promotion (for example, to contact you if you have won). We may also use the information to send you newsletters and other information we think may be of interest. Recipients of our mailings can unsubscribe by following instructions that may appear at the end of the email communication. Any personal information we collect may be associated with registration information. We may share aggregate information with others. We may sometimes partner with sponsors in offering contests, sweepstakes or surveys, and may share (provide and receive) information with them. By entering or participating in such contests, sweepstakes, and surveys, you affirmatively consent to our collection and use of your data.

## Data Collection

Our web sites have features that automatically collect information from users to assist us in creating sites that honor our users’ preferences and serve their interests and needs. These are often referred to as “cookies”.  These are very small data files containing information about the user that are stored on the user’s hard drive. Some cookies are used to make login to our sites easier (such as by remembering usernames and passwords). Cookies can also enable us to track users’ movements and target their interests to enhance their experience at our sites. We may also collect clickstream data and assign unique identifiers to our users for the same purposes. Information obtained with these technologies may be associated with your personal information so we can better market to you and customize our advertisements and promotions to your interests.

Most common web browsers today, such as Firefox and Internet Explorer, allow you to modify your settings to block cookies for delete entirely, alert you every time they are being sent, or allow their use by only those web sites you choose.  Through the use of web logs or log files, we may also gather information such as the date, time, browser type, navigation history, and IP address of all visitors to our site(s). We use this information for our internal security audit log, trend analysis, and system administration, and to gather broad demographic information about our user base. We may associate this information with your personal information. By visiting our sites, you affirmatively consent to our collection, use, and distribution of your data.

## With Whom Your Information is Shared

Information provided on SarahMclachlan.com will be used by Sarah McLachlan Entertainment, album label and Taylor & Pond Corporate Communications (website managers). We will not provide your information to other third parties with whom we have business relationships however we may choose to share the benefits of these relationships with you. By visiting our sites, you affirmatively consent to our collection, use, and distribution of your data.

Other than as set forth in this policy, we do not share your personally identifiable information with other companies, apart from those acting as our agents in providing our service to you, and which agree to use it only for that purpose and to keep the information secure and confidential. We will also disclose information we maintain when required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena or other legal obligation, in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property.

We may share (provide and receive) aggregate information, which is not personally identifiable, with others. This information may include demographic data such as the gender and/or geographic location of groups of users, but it will not include personal information (such as your name or email address). We use aggregate demographic information about our audience in order to improve our service, for research purposes, marketing/promotional purposes and/or for industry reporting purposes, among others.

## Communication and Choice

By accepting this privacy policy, you expressly choose to receive certain communications from us and third parties, and you expressly agree to the privacy practices described herein. Our site may also provide you with additional specific opportunities to select communications you wish to receive. You may change your privacy preferences, e.g. choose to cease receiving certain communications, by informing us of your new preferences. We will be able to honor your new preferences most quickly if you inform us of them by following the appropriate instructions in any communication you receive from us. Please be aware that messages you receive from us through SMS and instant messaging systems (and other systems apart from email) may not include an option to cease receiving communications; to change your privacy preferences with respect to those communications, please go to the profile page at the site where you provided your personal information or direct your instructions to the Contact identified at the end of this policy.

## Access

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code), we endeavor to provide a way to correct or update that user’s personal data. Please feel free to contact us if you have any questions regarding making changes to your data.

## Data Collection from Children

We strive to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We do not knowingly collect personal information from U.S. children under 13 without appropriate parental notice and consent. Sites that are directed to children where personal information is collected should have a Children’s Privacy Policy setting forth our COPPA-compliant practices. At many sites, we actively screen-out children from data collection and/or use of interactive or community features. We are committed to protecting children’s privacy.

**NOTICE: Visit[www.ftc.gov/kidzprivacy](http://www.ftc.gov/kidzprivacy)** **for information from the Federal Trade Commission about protecting children’s privacy online.**

## Security

Security for all personally identifiable information is extremely important to us. We store your personal information securely, and use special procedures designed to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction.

## Store/E-Commerce

Personal information collected in the store or e-commerce area is not shared without the purchasers’ consent. If you opt-in to the newsletter or similar then the previously described policies kick in.

## 3rd Party Links

We may provide links to non SarahMcLachlan.com sites such as news, ticket sites etc…. We are not responsible for those other sites, their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users, and we advise you to check their privacy policies.

## Changing our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify, alter or otherwise update this Privacy Policy at any time, so we encourage you to review this policy from time to time. Changes to this privacy policy are effective at the time they are posted and your continued use of our sites after posting will constitute acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those changes. 

## You Can Always Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please feel free to contact us at:

**Sarah McLachlan Entertainment**  
1489 Marine Drive, Suite 503  
West Vancouver, BC V7T 1B8 CA  
(619) 297-3742 or [email us](http://www.sarahmclachlan.com/contact/)  

For any Web Errors or Issues:

**Taylor & Pond Corporate Communications**  
2308 Kettner Blvd, Ste C  
San Diego, CA 92101 or [email here](http://www.taylorpond.com/contact/)
